Boris Drucker Papers
Boris Drucker Papers
1945-2004
Drucker, Boris.
33 linear ft.
Papers of the American cartoonist, illustrator. Original cartoons (1967-1986); memorabilia including a scrapbook of sketches made in India, 1945; and material on his children's book, Henrietta.
148953
Biographical History
Boris Drucker was an American artist, illustrator and cartoonist. Drucker lived and worked in Philadelphia for most of his career, and died there in January 2009.
Boris Drucker was born in Center City Philadelphia on 22 May 1920. After graduating from West Philadelphia High School in 1938, he received his training at the Pennsylvania Museum School of Industrial Art (later known as the Philadelphia College of Art, now part of the University of the Arts in Philadelphia). Drucker got his start in magazine publishing in 1946, when he had come back from his overseas experience in the Second World War. His final years at the art school had put him on an advertising track, and from the late 1940s until the middle of the 1960s, this is what he pursued in Philadelphia.
In 1966, after a brief stint of teaching advertising and commercial art, Drucker went to New York to open a studio and at the age of forty-six was accepted as a New Yorker cartoonist. The third phase of Drucker' s career had started. Cartooning and advertising had been the two main pillars of his early work, but he began to work more directly for industry clients for whom cartoon illustrations communicated more clearly than photographs. Along the way, Drucker found time to work up various ideas for cartoon strips, including a 1960s proposal for Future Boy. In the last phase of his productive and varied career, Drucker concentrated on commercial work for industry clients and created batch after batch of cartoons that commented on the passing scene with his unique attitude and drawing style. In addition to hundreds of published works, he produced approximately twelve thousand rough drawings that he donated to the Special Collections Research Center.
After all these years of having his work published and with all the recognition he has received, Drucker commented that "You never loose the kick of seeing your work in print."
In 2005 Syracuse University sponsored a retrospective exhibition of Boris Drucker’s work “Don’t Pay Any Attention To Him, He’s 90% Water” at the Louise and Bernard Palitz Gallery in New York.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Boris Drucker Papers includes original artwork, correspondence, sketchbooks, cartoons, personal memorabilia, scrapbooks, and illustrations for his children's book, Henrietta. The collection is currently undergoing extensive reprocessing to incorporate new material.
Arrangement of the Collection
Original cartoons are arranged based on numbers assigned to them by Drucker. Commercial art is arranged alphabetically by client/company name. Cartoon series are arranged alphabetically by name of the series. Published cartoons are arranged alphabetically by name of publication in which they appeared. Correspondence is alphabetical by correspondent. Memorabilia is alphabetical by type or topic.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Art -- Illustrators; Drucker, Boris.; Drucker, Boris -- Henrietta.; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Commercial art.; Cartoons (humorous images); Sketches.; Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Boris Drucker, 1966-1987.
Inventory
- Artwork
  - Original cartoons
    - #1 - #2099 (Box 1)
    - #2100 - #4209 (Box 2)
    - #4210 - #5998 (Box 3)
    - #5999 - #7402 (Box 4)
    - #7403 - #10907 (Box 5)
    - #10908 - #12615 (Box 6)
    - #12617-12895 and unnumbered (Box 6A)
  - Commercial art
    - American Telephone and Telegraph, undated (Box 7)
    - American Telephone and Telegraph (oversize), undated (Oversize 1)
    - American Tobacco Company, 1960 (Box 7)
    - American Veterinary Medical Association, undated (Box 7)
    - America’s Independent Electric Light and Power Companies, 1956 (Box 7)
    - Armstrong Cork Company, 1978 (Oversize 1)
    - Atlantic Richfield Company, 1977 (Box 7)
    - Atlas Powder Company, 1959 (Oversize 1)
    - Attapulgus Minerals & Chemicals Corporation, 1964 (Oversize 1)
    - Avis Rent-A-Truck, undated (Oversize 1)
    - Avisco Films, See FMC Corporation
    - Balmoral Beach Hotel Nassau, Bahamas, undated (Box 7)
    - Beryllium Corporation, undated (Box 7)
    - Bethlehem Steel, 1982; 1987,; 1989,; undated (Box 7)
    - Bissell Carpet Sweeper Company of Canada, 1956 (Oversize 1)
    - Blue Bell, Inc., 1959 (Oversize 1)
    - Blue Cross Blue Shield, 1960; undated (Box 7)
    - Breyers Ice Cream, undated (Box 7)
    - Brooklyn Union Gas Company, 1953 (Oversize 1)
    - Campus Direct, See Student Advantage, Inc..
    - Cannon Mills, Inc., 1948 (Oversize 1)
    - Certainteed Corporation, undated (Box 7)
    - Champion Spark Plugs, 1962 (Oversize 1)
    - Chevrolet, 1953 (Oversize 1)
    - Christ Episcopal Church Woodbury, MN, 1966 (Box 7)
    - Chrysler Corporation, 1952 (Oversize 1)
    - Chrysler Corporation, Parts Division, 1956 (Oversize 1)
    - Compensation and Capital, Incorporated, 1980 (Box 7)
    - Comptometer, See Felt & Tarrant Manufacturing Co.
    - Consolidated Cigar Corporation, 1958 (Oversize 2)
    - Consolidated Press, 1967 (Box 7)
    - Continental Can Company, 1972 (Box 7)
    - Dallas Transit System, 1983 (Box 7)
    - DeSoto, Inc., 1973-1975 (Box 7)
    - Devon Energy Corporation, 1983 (Box 7)
    - Diamond State Telephone Company, undated (Box 7)
    - Doktor Pet Center, 1968 (Box 7)
    - Drake Press, 1953; 1954 (Box 7)
    - DuPont, 1957 (Oversize 2)
    - EduWorld, Inc., 1970 (Box 7)
    - Ethicon Hospital Supplies, 1978; 1979 (Box 7)
    - Felt & Tarrant Manufacturing Co., 1948 (Oversize 2)
    - Fidelity Bank Philadelphia, PA, 1967 (Box 7)
    - Fidelity Mutual Life Insurance Company, 1964 (Box 7)
    - Fidelity Philadelphia Trust Company, 1950 (Oversize 2)
    - Finley Playground Philadelphia, PA, 1975; 1976 (Box 7)
    - Fiorillo, Maddalena attorney at law Tucson, AZ, 1998 (Box 7)
    - First National Safe Deposit Corporation Jenkintown, PA, 1980 (Box 7)
    - First Pennsylvania Banking and Trust Company Philadelphia, PA, 1956; 1958 (Box 7)
    - First Pennsylvania Banking and Trust Company Philadelphia, PA (oversize), 1956; 1958 (Oversize 2)
    - Florida Department of Commerce, undated (Box 7)
    - FMC Corporation Philadelphia, PA, 1965 (Box 7)
    - FMC Corporation Philadelphia, PA (oversize), 1956; 1958 (Oversize 2)
    - Frito-Lay, Inc., See Pepsico, Inc.
    - Gamble-Skogmo, Inc., 1980 (Box 7)
    - [W.W.] Grainger, Inc., 1977 (Box 7)
    - Gilbert/Commonwealth, Inc., 1984 (Box 7)
    - Gray & Rogers Advertising Philadelphia, PA, 1951 (Box 7)
    - GTE Sylvania Corporation, 1980 (Box 7)
    - Gulf Oil Corporation, 1963 (Box 7)
    - [P.H.] Hanes Knitting Company, 1957 (Oversize 2)
    - [A.S.] Hansen, Inc., 1971 (Box 7)
    - Hertz Corporation, undated (Box 7)
    - High Gradient, See Selas Corporation of America
    - Hills Brothers Coffee, Inc., undated (Box 7)
    - Hitchcock Clinic Hanover, NH, 1981 (Box 7)
    - Honeywell Corporation, 1980 (Box 7)
    - I-T-E Circuit Breaker Company, 1964-1967 (Oversize 2)
    - Insurance Company of North America, 1951; undated (Oversize 2)
    - Jason’s Chicken, Inc. Philadelphia, PA, 1978 (Box 7)
    - The Learning Child, 1971-1973 (Box 7)
    - Leath-Maxwell, 1972 (Box 7)
    - Lee Tires, 1953 (Oversize 2)
    - Leeds & Lippincott Company, 1957 (Box 7)
    - MHRA, 1977? (Box 7)
    - [P.R.] Mallory & Co., Inc., undated (Oversize 3)
    - Marathon Oil Corporation, undated (Box 7)
    - McCall’s, undated (Box 7)
    - Mead Paper, undated (Box 7)
    - Monitor Leasing and Financial Services, 1993-2006 (Oversize 3)
    - Morgan’s (restaurant) New York, NY, 1980 (Oversize 3)
    - National Fibre Company of Canada,Ltd., 1956 (Oversize 3)
    - National Football League Players’ Association, 1971 (Box 7)
    - New School for Social Research, 1981 (Box 7)
    - The New Yorker, 1988; 1990,; undated (Oversize 3)
    - Nicholson File, 1960 (Oversize 3)
    - Nordisk Pharmaceuticals (Denmark), 1984 (Box 7)
    - Olin, 1973 (Box 7)
    - Pelican Cove, FL, undated (Box 7)
    - Penn Salt, undated (Box 7)
    - The Pennsylvania Company, undated (Box 7)
    - Pennsylvania Railroad, undated (Box 7)
    - Pepsico, Inc, 1966 (Box 7)
    - Philadelphia Orchestra, 1972 (Box 7)
    - Philadelphia Savings Fund Society
      - Outdoor posters, 1950s-1960s (Box 7)
      - Annual reports, 1952; 1953 (Box 7)
      - Annual reports, 1954; 1955,; 1957,; 1959 (Box 8)
      - Christmas Club, 1964; undated (Box 8)
      - Newspaper ads, 1957 (Oversize 3)
      - Vacation Club, 1956-1959; undated (Oversize 3)
    - Phillies Cigars, See Consolidated Cigar Corporation
    - Polk Miller Products Corp., 1957 (Box 8)
    - Radio Corporation of America, 1969; undated (Box 8)
    - Risdon Corporation, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Rittenhouse-Fitler Square Neighborhood Security Committee Philadelphia, PA, 1997-2000 (Box 8)
    - Riverdale Country School Riverdale, NY, 1971 (Box 8)
    - Rohm and Haas Company, 1965-1967 (Oversize 3)
    - Royal Hawaiian Macadamia Nut Company, 1964 (Oversize 3)
    - Sand and Spray, See Leeds & Lippincott Company
    - Savannah Foods, Inc., 1992 (Box 8)
    - Seabrook Farms, 1956 (Box 8)
    - Sealtest, 1957 (Box 8)
    - Securities Industry Automation Corporation, 1972 (Box 8)
    - Selas Corporation of America, 1968-1969 (Box 8)
    - Sergeant’s, See Polk Miller Products
    - Sewell Corporation, 1988 (Box 8)
    - Sharp & Dohme, 1952 (Box 8)
    - Sorbus Inc., 1980 (Box 8)
    - Standard Products, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Stevens Textiles, 1968-1970 (Box 8)
    - Student Advantage, Inc., undated (Box 8)
    - Stylepark Hats, Inc., undated (Box 8)
    - The Sunday Bulletin Philadelphia, PA, 1963 (Oversize 3)
    - Turnkey (Chicago), 1976 (Box 8)
    - TV Guide, 1960; 1971,; undated (Oversize 3)
    - Unifirst Federal Savings Bank Building Hollywood, FL, 1986 (Box 8)
    - United Energy Services Corporation, undated (Oversize 3)
    - Valley Forge Convention and Visitors’ bureau, undated (Oversize 3)
    - Voice Processing Equipment Company, 1989 (Oversize 3)
    - Whitman’s Chocolates, 1956 (Oversize 3)
    - Yale & Towne, 1964 (Oversize 3)
    - Yellow Cab Company of Philadelphia, undated (Oversize 3)
    - Yes Tissues, 1947 (Oversize 3)
    - Unidentified (Oversize 5)
  - Cartoon series
    - Animal Alphabet (Oversize 4)
      See also Published cartoons: Good Housekeeping (Box 9)
    - Cliff and Ivy (Oversize 4)
    - Future Boy (Oversize 4)
    - Look at the State They’re In, 2 folders (Oversize 4)
      See also Published cartoons: Saturday Evening Post (Box 9)
    - Miles Hai (Oversize 4)
    - The Perfect Squelch, 5 folders (Oversize 4A)
    - Victoria and Ivy (Oversize 4)
    - You Be the Judge (Oversize 4)
  - Finished cartoons (sold)
    - Identified (Oversize 6)
    - Identified (Oversize 7)
    - Unidentified (Oversize 8)
    - Unidentified (Oversize 8A)
    - Unidentified (Oversize 9)
    - Unidentified (Oversize 9A)
    - Unidentified (Oversize 10)
  - Published cartoons
    - Argosy, undated (Box 9)
    - Changing Times, 1971-1980 (Box 9)
    - Colliers, 1946-1955 (Box 9)
    - Common Cents, 1977-1978 (Box 9)
    - Cosmopolitan, 1973-1974 (Box 9)
    - Family Week, 1965; 1971 (Box 9)
    - Good Housekeeping, 1971 (Box 9)
      See also Cartoon series: Animal Alphabet (Oversize 4)
    - Holiday, 1951; 1953,; undated (Box 9)
    - Horticulture, 1984 (Box 9)
    - Ladies Home Journal, 1969 (Box 9)
    - Look, 1962-1971 (Box 9)
    - Managed Care, 1994 (Box 9)
    - Medical Economics, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Medical Opinion & Review, 1971 (Box 9)
    - Modern Maturity, 1993-1994 (Box 9)
    - Natural History, 1993 (Box 9)
    - Monitor, 2005 (Box 9)
    - The New Yorker, 1971-1997; undated; 7 folders (Box 9)
    - OBG Management, 1991; 1992,; 1994,; undated (Box 9)
    - Parade, 1957 (Box 9)
    - Parents, 1992; 1993 (Box 9)
    - Pediatric Management, 1991; 1992,; 1994,; undated (Box 9)
    - Playboy, 1976-1995; undated (Box 9)
    - Punch, 1968-1969; 1988-1989 (Box 9)
    - Saturday Evening Post, 1946-1973; undated; 6 folders (Box 9)
      See also the following under Artwork: Cartoon series:
      Look at the State They’re In
      The Perfect Squelch
      You Be the Judge
    - The Saturday Review, 1971-1972; 1974 (Box 9)
    - Suburbia Today, 1962-1963 (Box 9)
    - This Week, 1951-1952; 1954,; 1968-1969 (Box 9)
    - Smoke, 1996; 1998,; 2000 (Box 9)
    - Sports Illustrated, 1955 (Box 9)
    - Time, 1976 (Box 9)
    - Tour, 1980 (Box 9)
    - True, 1953; 1968-1972,; undated (Box 9)
    - TV Guide, 1971 (Box 9)
    - U.S. News & World Report, 1979 (Box 9)
    - V ista of the United Nations Association, 1968; undated (Box 9)
    - World, 1973 (Box 9)
    - Unidentified (Box 9)
  - Student artwork
    - Watercolor, 1934 (Box 9)
    - Pennsylvania Museum School of Industrial Art, 1940; 1941 (Box 9)
    - Pennsylvania Museum School of Industrial Art (oversize), 1940; 1941 (Oversize 1)
    - Army sketches, 1943-1946; undated; 4 folders (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous sketches (Box 9)
- Correspondence/subject files
  - Changing Times (Box 10)
  - Devine, Rose, See "Perfect Menus for Perfect Dinner Parties" (Box 10)
  - Drucker, A. B. (Box 10)
  - Foster, — (Box 10)
  - Gilliam, Art (Box 10)
  - Gray & Rogers (Box 10)
  - Gross, Sam (Box 10)
  - Hallmark Cards (Box 10)
  - Hams, Jud (Box 10)
  - Junior Miss (Box 10)
  - Lafferty, Mary Loretta, See "Perfect Menus for Perfect Dinner Parties" (Box 10)
  - National Peace Action Coalition (Box 10)
  - The New Yorker (Box 10)
  - Pennsylvania Museum School of Industrial Art (Box 10)
  - "Perfect Menus for Perfect Dinner Parties" (Box 10)
  - Philadelphia Museum of Art, See Pennsylvania Museum School of Industrial Art
  - Random House (Box 10)
  - Saturday Evening Post (Box 10)
  - United States Army Air Force Personnel Distribution Command (Box 10)
  - Wall Street Journal (Box 10)
  - West Philadelphia High School (Box 10)
  - Wither, Barbara, 3 folders (Box 10)
- Writings
  - Books
    - Henrietta (Oversize 11)
- Memorabilia
  - Clippings, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Clippings (oversize) (Oversize 12)
  - Exhibition: "Don't pay any attention to him, he's 90% water." (Oversize 13)
  - Military, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Photographs, 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook, 1958; 6 folders (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 14)